hey what's up guys my name is Aero and
welcome to a brand new series this
series is going to teach you everything
you need to know about C++ we're going
to learn C++ specifically in the context
of game development however it's not
just going to apply to game development
or game programming we're just going to
use games as an example this series is
going to apply to pretty much everyone
whether you're a beginner or you're
Advanced we'll cover the basics of the
language but we'll be quite concise with
that so basically if you are a beginner
you can still follow along with this
series but you're going to have to be
able to Google things and do some
research and find find some of the
basics out for yourself basically just
be a normal person and Google things
that you don't understand I don't want
to dwell on the basics for too long and
cover them in extreme detail so just
make sure you Google things and you'll
be fine so now the question is why why
would I want to learn C++ isn't C++ kind
of an outdated language why what good is
there in learning C++ nowadays so C++ is
still pretty much the most used language
when you need to write fast code that
performs well or if you're writing for a
weird AR arure or a platform and you
need the code to run natively if you
want direct control over Hardware C++ is
for you the games industry for example
uses C++ extensively and game engines
like Unity unreal frostbite they're all
written in C++ so the question is why
why would we want direct access to
Hardware why are all of these game
engines written in C++ why not use
another language the biggest reason for
using C++ is the direct control over
Hardware let's talk a little bit about
how C++ works so you write your code in
C++ you pass your code into compiler and
that compiler will output machine code
for your Target platform machine code is
the actual instructions that your
devic's CPU will actually perform so
using C++ we can literally control every
single instruction that your CPU
executes what platforms the C++ run on
you ask pretty much anything you just
need a compiler that will output machine
code for that platform for example an
x64 compiler will output x64 machine
code and thus run on x64 CPUs so to give
you an example of some of theat
platforms that C++ is commonly used to
develop for Windows Mac Linux any other
desktop operating systems pretty much
all of them mobile operating systems iOS
Android for example you can write
applications in C++ and all the consoles
so Xbox PlayStation all the Nintendo
stuff like the 3DS the Wii U the switch
everything C++ is great when you need
wide platform support because as long as
there's a compiler you can get C++ to
compile into native code that will run
on that platform of course there are are
other native languages out there it's
just that C++ is the one that's been
around since the early 80s and it's just
so popular and everyone knows it that
it's just everyone's using it other
languages like C or Java differ because
they run on a virtual machine this means
that your code gets compiled into an
Intermediate Language first and then
when you actually run your application
on that Target platform the VM the
virtual machine will basically converted
into machine code at runtime so picture
this if you will pretend that you wrote
a book in English but you want someone
some in Germany who only speaks German
to read your book so what you've decided
to do is actually sell the book in
English at the German store however when
you buy the book you also get like a
translator like an actual person to come
home with you I know this metaphor is
getting a bit weird but just bear with
me so the person comes home and then
when the when that German person wants
to read the book The translator reads
the book in English and then just
basically starts talking in German so
he's like live translating the whole
book for the person
that's kind of what running on a virtual
machine is like of course it would be a
lot more efficient if you just
translated the book itself into German
and then sold that in German stores so
that way it would be in the native
language in German and that's of course
not a perfect metaphor but that's kind
of what it's like to run C++ versus a
language like Java or C C++ is a native
language the C++ compiler produces
machine code for that Target platform
and for that Target architecture and
then that's it it's there it's native
code it will only run on that platform
platform however it's already in that
platform's machine code language so
there's absolutely no translation or
anything required you just run the M you
just push the machine code instructions
CPU instructions into the CPU and it
will perform all of your instructions of
course just because your code is native
doesn't mean it's going to be fast if
you write bad code in C++ it's going to
be slow in fact it'll likely even be
slower than virtual machine languages
like C or Java because they tend to
optimize things on the fly a lot better
than C++ will so if you right bad C++
C++ will definitely be slower than C or
Java and because of that I mean I love
using languages like C when I just need
a write tools or things that don't
necessarily need me to squeeze every bit
of performance out of them C is a
fantastic language for that but this
series is going to be for when we
actually need that performance for when
we need to write C++ so we're going to
learn all about how to write C++
correctly how to write good code how to
ride fast code so what are we going to
cover you may ask well of course from
the beginning we're going to start with
the basics I'm going to be real concise
when it comes to the basics cuz I don't
really want to dwell on them too much if
you've never programmed before I still
do encourage you to watch this series
but as I said earlier you're going to
have to just Google the things that you
don't understand it should be pretty
easy to follow the key to learning
anything new really is just to play
around with it and just to experiment
with it so I'm sure you'll be absolutely
fine if you're just passionate about it
and if you actually have the W the
willingness to learn we'll talk about
how to use C++ library to your advantage
and what things to kind of avoid if you
care about performance we'll talk about
how C++ actually works we'll talk about
stuff like memory and pointers seriously
this for some reason is taught
absolutely terribly in most cases so
we're going to actually teach pointers
and memory and stuff properly this time
memory Arenas custom allocators Smart
pointers move sematics stuff like that
templates and how to actually use them
properly if you know how to use
templates well they're extremely
powerful and they'll make your life a
lot easier we'll talk about stuff like
macros and how to program for multiple
platforms we'll write our own data
structures and learn how to make them a
lot faster than the standard ones you
get with the C++ Library we'll even
cover lowlevel optimization via compiler
intrinsics and assembly such as writing
our maths and S and that's pretty much
it we'll probably cover a lot of things
along the way if there are specific
things that you guys request or things
that probably could involve me talking
for 10 minutes about I might make a
separate video about them just in
general lastly if you want to know who I
am I'm a software engineer who on the
game engine team at EA Melbourne we make
pretty much the best 3D mobile game
engine out there so the games that we've
recently shipped were need to speed No
Limits and Need for Speed No Limits VR
you can follow me on Twitter or
Instagram if you want to get to know me
better episodes for this series will be
released around every week or so
depending on my schedule if you want to
support this series and ensure that the
videos get out as soon as possible and
you can do so by going to patreon.com
Theo other than that this series should
be an absolute blast I'm really looking
forward to it let's let C++ correctly
I'll see you guys next week goodbye
Voom